

Samuel S. Gibson

78 Cabin Bar Drive Clayton, NC 27520 919.815.2461 sgibson10@icloud.com github.com/Star-Gibson www.linkedin.com/in/stargibson/

Profile

Graduate of the International Studies program at the academically rigorous, North Carolina State University, with proven efficiency in the Chinese language. Currently enrolled in the UNC-Charlotte Coding Bootcamp to gain technical skills in software development that I can combine with my vast knowledge to the technology space from previous opportunities. Upon completion of the program, I look forward to implementing my new skill set and obtaining a role as a Junior Web Developer.

Forward thinking professional with hands on experience in a variety of diverse environments, both in the United States and abroad. Reliable and responsible individual who is able to provide leadership when collaborating with others, but also possesses the mental fortitude to work well independently.

Employment History

ettain group – Charlotte, NC	Technical Recruiter	01/2020 - 05/2020
ettain group – Raleigh & Charlotte, NC	Resource Specialist	02/2019 - 01/2020
Cloud Harvest – Raleigh, NC	Account Manager	01/2018 - 11/2018
Planet Fitness – Cary, NC	Front Desk Supervisor	03.2016 - 2.2017 / 6.2017 - 11.2017
WCPSS – Raleigh, NC	Substitute Teacher	12.2016 - 04.2017

Experience

Technical Skills

- ➤ Software Development: JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Bulma, Invision, Github, MomentJS, API Integration
- ➤ Able to create, modify, and utilize Microsoft software (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
- > Certified in Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, and Microsoft Powerpoint
- ➤ Adept problem solver
- ➤ Reviewed invoices via ABC, QuickBooks and cross-referenced with client billing statements in order to settle any discrepancies.
- ➤ Intermediate level Chinese language skills

Communication

Fostered relationships with potential candidates in the Raleigh and Charlotte market while supporting Cisco, Bank of America, Wells Fargo, Caring LLC, Pratt & Miller, Lowe's, Harris Teeter, Kroger, Atrium, Premier Inc, Bioventus, and various other clients.

- > Provided insight into opportunities ranging from Help Desk to Director of Business Intelligence, while affording potential qualified candidates the ability to make a change in career.
- Effectively communicated Cloud Harvest's IT asset recovery service to organizations to partners, as well as customers in the efforts to return initial cap-ex as the transition to an op-ex model occurs
- ➤ Initiated and formed partnerships with 10 organizations, with primary focus on partnering with and understanding the AWS (LATAM, US) sales team and cycle.
- Able to generate solutions swiftly to newly encountered situations by implementing the Pause, Acknowledge, Clarify, and Respond technique (P.A.C.R)
- > Communicated and interacted with native Chinese speakers to navigate while abroad
- Ability to convey teaching points in a purposeful manner to my students

Global Preparedness

- Traveled abroad to gain new deeper and further my perspectives and understanding of culture: China (7 wks.), Greece (14 days)
- ➤ Participated in the International Friendship Program and the Confucius Institute to further my Chinese language skills while improving my understanding of the Chinese language.

Education

- ➤ UNC-Charlotte Coding Bootcamp Charlotte, NC (In-Progress)
- ➤ Bachelor of Arts, International Studies: North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC
- ➤ Nanjing Normal University: Mandarin Language Immersion, Nanjing, China (Certificate of Completion)
- > Diploma, North Carolina School of Science and Math: Durham, NC